<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gabor Parti</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gabor Parti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nutmeg in the flag of Grenada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/grenada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/grenada/</guid>
      <description>I have been drawing flags ever since I was a kid, and all my life I thought that the Grenadian flag has tiny little flame. Now, after spending 3 years on a PhD thesis about spices, I found out that the flag features an open nutmeg fruit (Myristica fragrans), for its important role in the island&amp;rsquo;s economy. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that neat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The .io Domain Name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/io/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/io/</guid>
      <description>What is the .io domain name and why is it problematic?&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Preferred by tech companies, the .io domain name does not actually refer to the input-output word pair (I/O) we all learned about in primary school. I still remember that IT teacher - Gyuri bácsi - with the black mustache and white lab-coat trying to calm us down when the first Windows 98 PCs arrived. We suddenly got slapped in the face by the ever-accelerating pace of technology and subsequently forgot all our (very limited) MS-DOS skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fonts &amp; Typography</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fonts/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes regarding fonts, typography, and typesetting.&#xA;Fonts&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;The Brill&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;This is a brilliant typeface for academic publishing. It is a serif typeface designed by Dalton Maag. It is a custom typeface for the academic publisher Brill, and it is available for free for non-commercial use. It is a serif typeface with a large x-height, and it is designed to be legible in small sizes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set up LaTeX for Multiscripted Documents.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/latex-multiscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/latex-multiscript/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample preamble of a LaTeX file I use for writing multiscripted documents, where the main document language is English (see full MWE at the end). This is currently the best way I have found so far to make it all work in the simplest way possible, including Chinese, Japanese, Korean (CJK), right-to-left scripts (RTL), and rendering Devanagari ligatures &amp;ndash; all with a harmonious look and feel. I think academic publishers and typsetters are still scared of using &amp;ldquo;foreign scripts&amp;rdquo; in publications, maybe this can help a few people to include them more in their LaTeX documents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use LaTeX offline with VSCode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/latex-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/latex-vscode/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build and Host a Website with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>This is a concise, step-by-step guide on how to build a website - just like this one - with Hugo, and host it on Github. Follow the steps and check out the links for further explanation on each component. This guide is made for non-experts, because I found most Hugo tutorials utterly useless and sparse for people new to computers web-development.&#xA;It might look daunting at first to go through all these steps below, but the reward is that once you get it right, updating and maintaining your website will be incredibly fast and easy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Publish a Python Package: A Rudimentary Pipeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/python-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/python-package/</guid>
      <description>PIPELINE&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;This is a concise step by step rough-guide on how to package and publish an open source python project, accompanied by an auto-generated documentation website (readthedocs.io). This post are my own notes for my future self in case I forget how to do this, so the explanations are minimal. If lost, follow the actual tutorials in the footnotes.&#xA;Sources and links to tutorials on the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/markdown-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/markdown-syntax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following markdown file showcases all the features one can achieve within markdown and with Hugo shortcodes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;markdown-format&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  MARKDOWN FORMAT&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#markdown-format&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
